Helle collection of Plath family photographs, 1910-1963
Mortimer Rare Book Room
Helle collection of Plath family photographs
1910-1963
273
1 box (.5 linear ft.)
Mortimer Rare Book Room Smith College Northampton, MA
This collection of Plath family photographs includes photographs of Otto Plath and his siblings, of Aurelia Schober Plath, Warren and Sylvia Plath and various other Schober relatives.
Historical Note
Otto Emil Plath (1885-1940) was a German instructor and biology professor at Boston University, 1922-1940. Born in Grabow, Germany, on April 13, 1885, to Theodore and Ernestine Kottke Platt, he was the eldest of six children. Otto Plath was educated at Northwestern College, Wisconsin (A.B., 1910), University of Washington (M.A., 1912), Harvard University (M.S., 1925; Sc.D., 1928). In 1932 he married Aurelia Frances Schober (1906-1994) who later became an associate professor in the College of Practical Arts and Letters at Boston University, 1942-1971.
They lived at 24 Prince Street, Jamaica Plain, Massachusetts, until 1936 when the family moved to 92 Johnson Avenue, Winthrop, Massachusetts, to be near Aurelia's parents-Frank Schober (1880-1965) and Aurelia Greenwood Schober (1887-1956)-and Aurelia's siblings Dorothy Schober Benotti (1911-1981) and Frank Richard Schober (1919- ). Otto Plath died on November 5, 1940 from complications of diabetes.
Otto and Aurelia Schober Plath had two children: Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) and Warren Joseph Plath (1935- ). In 1942, Aurelia Plath moved to 26 Elmwood Road, Wellesley, Massachusetts, with her daughter, son, and her parents.
Sylvia Plath graduated from Smith College (B.A., 1955) and Newnham College, Cambridge (M.A., 1957). Warren Plath graduated from Harvard College (A.B. 1957) and Harvard University (Ph.D., 1964). He was a Fulbright student at the University of Bonn, 1957-1958.
On June 16, 1956, 1956, Sylvia Plath married English poet Ted Hughes (1930-1998). Plath and Hughes honeymooned in Benidorm, Spain, visiting Paris en route where they met Warren Plath. Sylvia Plath and Ted Hughes had two children: Frieda Rebecca Hughes (1960- ) and Nicholas Farrar Hughes (1962- ). Frieda Hughes was born on April 1, 1960 at home at 3 Chalcot Square in London near Primrose Hill. Nicholas Hughes was born on January 17, 1962 at home at Court Green in North Tawton, Devonshire, England. Before her death on February 11, 1963, Plath published The Colossus & Other Poems and her novel The Bell Jar. Her Collected Poems, published posthumously in 1981, won the Pulitzer Prize.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Helle Collection of Plath Family Photographs was assembled by June Johnson Helle with additions from her mother, Martha Plath Johnson, and her aunt, Frieda Plath Heinrichs, who were sisters of Otto Emil Plath. Some of the photographs were originally sent by Aurelia Plath to her sister-in-laws Frieda Plath Heinrichs and Martha Plath Johnson. June Johnson Helle served as executor for the personal belongings of her mother and aunt Frieda Plath Heinrichs. The photographs are annotated by Otto Plath, Aurelia Schober Plath, Sylvia Plath, and June Johnson Helle.
The collection is arranged as follows:
Series I. Photographs of Otto Plath and Siblings (1910-1930s) contains 8 items. These photographs of Otto Plath and his brother Hugo Plath and sister Frieda Plath are arranged in chronological order.
Series II. Photographs of Sylvia Plath and others (1933-1963) contains 51 items. These photographs of Sylvia Plath, Aurelia Schober Plath, Otto Plath, Warren Plath and their Schober relatives are arranged in chronological order.
Series III. Other photographs contains one postcard of Berck-Plage.
Organization of the Collection
This collection is organized into three series:
Series I. Photographs of Otto Plath and Siblings, 1910-1930s
Series II. Photographs of Sylvia Plath and others, 1933-1963
Series III. Other photographs, n.d.
The photographs are open to research according to the regulations of the Mortimer Rare Book Room.
The Plath Family Photographs were donated by Anita Helle, daughter of June Johnson Helle, to the Mortimer Rare Book Room in 2006.
Plath, Aurelia Schober; Plath, Sylvia- Pictoral works; Plath, Otto Emil, 1885-1940; Plath, Warren, 1935-; Poets, American- 20th century- Biography- Sources; Helle, June Johnson
Related materials can be found in these other repositories: Sylvia Plath Collection, Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana; Ted Hughes Papers, Robert W. Woodruff Library, Emory University, Atlanta, Georgia.
- SERIES I. Photographs of Otto Plath and Siblings
  - Studio photograph of Otto Plath[ca. 1910], Black and white photograph. 7 x 13.7 cm.; Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Otto Plath. Subject: Full view of Otto Plath (1885-1940) wearing a band uniform and holding an oboe. © Estate of Otto Plath (Helle 1)
  - Postcard photograph of Otto Plath with his classmates at Northwestern College[ca.1910], Black and white photograph. 13.8 x 8.7 cm.; Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Otto Plath (Indicated) with U/College group. Subject: Otto Plath (1885-1940), third from left in the front row. Some men hold steins and various musical instruments. © Estate of Otto Plath (Helle 2)
  - Studio photograph of Otto Plath in cap and gown 1910, Black and white photograph. 7 x 14 cm.; Caption on verso by ?Otto Plath: Otto Plath graduates Nwestern 1910. Subject: Full view of Otto Plath (1885-1940) wearing a cap and gown. © Estate of Otto Plath (Helle 3)
  - Studio photograph of Otto Plath in cap and gown[1910], Black and white photograph. 9.8 x 15 cm.; Subject: Head and shoulders view of Otto Plath (1885-1940) wearing a cap and gown. © Estate of Otto Plath (Helle 4)
  - Studio photograph of Otto Plath[ca.1911], Black and white photograph. 6.5 x 12 cm. in a folder 8 x 14.5 cm.; Blind stamped on folder: J T Long / Seattle Subject: Head and shoulders view of Otto Plath (1885-1940) wearing a suit and tie. © Estate of Otto Plath (Helle 5)
  - Studio photograph of Frieda and Hugo Plath 1917, Black and white photograph. 12.5 x 20 cm.; Blind stamped on recto: Stafford / 69th & Halsted / Chicago Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Frieda and Hugo Plath / sister and brother / 1917. Subjects: Full view of Frieda Plath Heinrichs and Hugo Plath, wearing a uniform, seated on a table. © Estate of Frieda Plath Heinrichs (Helle 6)
  - Anonymous. Otto Plath with a colleague, [1920s], Black and white photograph. 8.3 x 11 cm.; Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Otto Plath with a colleague. Stamped on verso: Films Developed Free S. N. Wood Photo Finisher 46 Cornhill, Boston Subject: Full view of Otto Plath (1885-1940) with an unidentified colleague. Both men are wearing suits and standing in a back yard near a house. © Unknown (Helle 7)
  - Studio photograph of Otto Plath[1930s], Black and white photograph. 10 x 14.5 cm. in a folder 16 x 23.5 cm.; Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: O.E. Plath / A few years before his death. He was already ill... Stamped on folder: Sargent Studio / 154 Boylston Street / Boston Subject: Head and shoulders view of Otto Plath (1885-1940) wearing a checked coat and tie. © Estate of Otto Plath (Helle 8)
- SERIES II. Photographs of Sylvia Plath and her family
  - Anonymous. Baby Sylvia Plath sitting on her mother's lap April 1933, Black and white photograph. 7.2 x 9.8 cm.; Caption on recto by Aurelia Plath: 5 months Caption on verso by Aurelia Plath: April 1933 / Sylvia - 5 months Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Aurelia and Sylvia Plath Subject: Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) and her mother, Aurelia Schober Plath (1906-1994). Three quarter view of Aurelia sitting on a chair outside near a chain fence holding Sylvia on her lap. Aurelia is wearing a dark coat with fur trim and hat. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 9)
  - Anonymous. Baby Sylvia Plath laughing [May 1933], Black and white photograph. 7 x 9.3 cm.; Caption on recto by Aurelia Plath: Sylvia / is always / merry! / 7 months Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Sylvia Plath Subject: Three quarter view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) wearing a bonnet and laughing. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 10)
  - Anonymous. Baby Sylvia Plath [May 1933], Black and white photograph. 47 x 9.3 cm.; Caption on recto by Aurelia Plath: 7 / months / old Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Sylvia Plath Subject: Three quarter view of baby Sylvia Plath (1932-1963), gazing up at the unidentified person who holds her on his/her lap. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 11)
  - Anonymous. Baby Sylvia Plath with her grandmother and motherJuly 1933, Black and white photograph. 6.5 x 9 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Plath: July 1933 / my mother, Sylvia and I. Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Aurelia, her mother (Mrs.Schober), and Sylvia. Stamped on verso: A 6. Note: Possibly taken by Otto Plath at the Arnold Arboretum Subject: Aurelia Greenwood Schober (1887-1956) (left), Aurelia Schober Plath (1906-1994) (right), and Sylvia Plath (1932-1963). Baby Sylvia sits on a blanket in front of her grandmother and mother kneeling behind her on the grass. © Estate of Otto Plath (Helle 12)
  - Anonymous. Plath Family (Aurelia, Sylvia, and Otto Plath)July 1933, Black and white photograph. 6.5 x 9 cm.; Caption on recto by Aurelia Plath: The Plath Family - July 1933 Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Aurelia - Sylvia - Otto. Stamped on verso: A 19 Note: Possibly taken by Aurelia Greenwood Schober at the Arnold Arboretum. Subject: Sylvia Plath (1932-1963), Aurelia Schober Plath (1906-1994), and Otto Plath (1885-1940). Three quarter view of Otto Plath sitting next to Aurelia with baby Sylvia on her lap. © Estate of Aurelia Greenwood Schober (Helle 13)
  - Anonymous. Baby Sylvia PlathJuly 1934, Black and white photograph. 6.5 x 8.7 cm.; Caption on recto by Aurelia Plath, July 1934-20 months old Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Sylvia Plath Subject: Full view of baby Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) sitting in a pan on the lawn near a sandbox. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 14)
  - Anonymous. Warren and Sylvia PlathDecember 1935, Black and white photograph. 6.2 x 8.7 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Plath: Winthrop, December 1935. Warren is being restrained, not upheld. Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Warren and Sylvia Plath Stamp on verso: Knox Photo Medford, Mass. 808 Subject: Warren Plath (1935- ) and Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) dressed in warm clothes standing near a tree in Winthrop, Massachusetts. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 15)
  - Anonymous. Sylvia Plath pushing her brother in a strollerDecember 1935, Black and white photograph. 6.2 x 8.7 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Plath: Winthrop-Dec. 1935 Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Warren and Sylvia Plath Stamp on verso: Knox Photo Medford, Mass. 808 Subject: Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) pushing her brother, Warren Plath (1935- ), in a stroller on a sidewalk in Winthrop, Massachusetts. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 16)
  - Anonymous. Sylvia Plath and her mother at Winthrop Beachca. July 1936, Black and white photograph. 6 x 8.7 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Plath: Sylvia & mother at Winthrop Beach. Stamp on verso: Knox photo Medford, Mass. 813 Subject: Nearly full view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) and her mother, Aurelia Schober Plath (1906-1994), sitting in the grass at Winthrop Beach. Both are wearing dresses and a house is in the background. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 17)
  - Anonymous. Sylvia Plath with her mother and aunt at Point Shirley, Winthrop, Massachusettsca. 1936, Black and white photograph. 11.5 x 8 cm.; Caption on version by June Johnson Helle: Aurelia's brother (?) / Aurelia & sister and Sylvia Plath. Note: Probably taken by Sylvia Plath's grandfather, Frank Schober (1880-1965). Subject: Head and shoulder view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963), Aurelia Schober Plath (1906-1994), and Dorothy Schober Benotti (1911-1981) on the beach at Point Shirley in Winthrop, Massachusetts. Aurelia's uncle Henry Schober may be in the background. © Estate of Frank Schober (Helle 18)
  - Anonymous. Sylvia Plath at Winthrop Beach ca. July 1936, Black and white photograph. 6.2 x 8.7 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Plath: Sylvia-3 yrs. 9 mos. Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Sylvia Plath Stamp on verso: 867 Subject: Full view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) standing in the water at Winthrop Beach. She is wearing a bathing suit and a large bow in her hair. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 19)
  - Studio portrait of Sylvia and Warren Plath 1937, Black and white photograph. 12.2 x 20.2 cm.; Caption on recto by Aurelia Plath: To Aunt Frieda & Uncle Walter / from Sylvia & / Warren, May 1937. Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Sylvia and Warren Plath. Sylvia is 4½ / Warren is 2. Subject: Head and shoulder view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) and Warren Plath (1935- ). Sylvia is wearing a bow in her hair. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 20)
  - Anonymous. Warren and Sylvia Plath on a swingAugust 1937, Black and white photograph, with deckle edges. 18 x 10.5 cm.; Printed caption on verso by Aurelia Plath: Warren & Sylvia enjoying the swing at grandmother's house. August, 1937. (Can't you just hear them laugh?) Stamp on verso: 696 Subject: Three quarter view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) on a swing in her grandparent's yard at Winthrop, Massachusetts, with Warren Plath (1935- ) in the foreground. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 21)
  - Anonymous. Sylvia Plath and her motherAugust 1937, Black and white photograph with deckle edges. 8 x 10.5 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Plath: Sylvia, holding "Baby Sue," and her mummy. August, 1937. Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Aurelia and Sylvia Plath. Stamp on verso: 696 Subject: Head and shoulders view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) and Aurelia Schober Plath (1906-1994) sitting on the front steps of their home in Winthrop, Massachusetts. Sylvia is holding a doll. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 22)
  - Anonymous. Warren and Sylvia Plath sledding[February 1939], Black and white photograph with deckle edges. 8 x 10.5cm.; Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Warren and Sylvia Plath-Boston, Mass. Stamp on verso: 242 Subject: Full view of Warren Plath (1935- ) lying on top of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) on a sled in the snow. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 23)
  - Anonymous. Sylvia Plath on the beach July 1939, Black and white photograph with deckle edges. 8.5 x 12.2 cm.; Caption on recto by Aurelia Plath: July 1939-Sylvia 6 yrs 9 months Subject: Full view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) wearing a one-piece bathing suit with an anchor design on the front. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 24)
  - Anonymous. Sylvia and Warren Plath on a sailboat in Winthrop, MassachusettsAugust 1940, Black and white photograph, trimmed. 6.5 x 11.2 cm.; Caption on recto by Aurelia Plath: August, 1940 / 7 years, 9 mo 5 years / Winthrop, Mass. Caption on verso by Aurelia Plath: Sylvia and Warren Aug. / 7 yrs. 9 mos. 5 yrs. 3 mos. Subject: Full view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) and Warren Plath (1935- ) on a beached sailboat. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 25)
  - Anonymous. Sylvia Plath nursing her dollSeptember 1940, Black and white photograph with deckle edges. 8 x 10.8 cm.; Caption on recto by Aurelia Plath: Sept. 1940 Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Sylvia, dressed as a nurse-taken during her father's illness Stamped on verso: 867 Subject: Three quarter view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) in the backyard with her doll wearing a nurses uniform and her hair in braids. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 26)
  - Anonymous. Wedding photograph of Joseph and Dorothy Benotti with Warren and Sylvia PlathApril 19, 1941, Black and white photograph with deckle edges. 11.5 x 8.2 cm.; Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Wedding of Aurelia's sister. Warren and Sylvia Plath stand in front. Stamp on verso: 540F Subject: Full view of Warren Plath (1935- ) and Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) standing in front of Joseph Benotti (1911-1996) and Dorothy Schober Benotti (1911-1981) on their wedding day. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 27)
  - Anonymous. Warren and Sylvia Plath holding a catAugust 1941, Black and white photograph with three holes at the top. 38.5 x 11 cm.; Caption on recto by Aurelia Schober Plath: August 1941 Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Warren and Sylvia Plath. Stamped on verso: 821C Genuine VELOX Photo Paper. ?Doll Dev., 8 prints, one hold-?pal album, The Baldwin Studio, St. Louis, MO 20¢ Subject: Three quarter view of Warren Plath (1935- ) and Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) holding Mitzi (cat) on the front porch of their house in Winthrop, Massachusetts. Sylvia's hair is in braids and the cat is wearing one of Sylvia's doll bonnets © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 28)
  - Anonymous. Wedding photograph of Frank and Louise Schober flanked by Warren and Sylvia PlathJune 27, 1942, Black and white photograph with deckle edges. 8 x 10.5 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: June 27, 1942 / my brother, Frank, and his bride Louise. Sylvia was flower-girl, and Warren was ring-bearer at the wedding. Sylvia's dress was of pale pink organza and its length thrilled her little heart! Frank is 6'2" tall; Louise is just 5'-so you see how tall my two babies have grown! Stamped on verso: 51 Subject: Full view of Warren Plath (1935- ) and Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) flanking Frank Richard Schober (1919- ) and Louise Bowman Schober (1920- ) on their wedding day. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 29)
  - Anonymous. Wedding photograph of Frank and Louise Schober flanked by Warren and Sylvia PlathJune 27, 1942, Black and white photograph, trimmed. 6.5 x 9 cm.; Caption on recto by Aurelia Schober Plath: Frank & Louise Schober / Warren-7½ Sylvia-9½ / Winthrop, Mass. / 1942. Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: My brother Frank Schober and his bride, Louise. Warren age 7 years / Sylvia " 9½ " / (Sylvia wants you to know her dress was made of pale pink organza and that the slip under it is pretty enough to be a dress too.) Subject: Full view of Warren Plath (1935- ) and Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) flanking Frank Richard Schober (1919- ) and Louise Bowman Schober (1920- ) on their wedding day. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 30)
  - Anonymous. Sylvia Plath in Wellesleyfall 1945, Black and white photograph. 9 x 6.5 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: Fall 1945. Caption on verso by Martha Johnson: On this picture Sylvia reminds me a little of you when you were that age. Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Sylvia Plath. Martha Johnson wrote the note above to daughter June. 9Blind stamp on verso: VELOX Subject: Three quarter view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) holding a jug on the front porch of her home in Wellesley, Massachusetts. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 31)
  - Anonymous. Sylvia and Warren PlathChristmas 1945, Black and white photograph. 6.5 x 9 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: Xmas 1945 Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Sylvia Plath age 13. Stamp on verso: VELOX Subject: Full view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) and Warren Plath (1935- ) on the front porch of their home in Wellesley, Massachusetts. Sylvia wears a scarf and kneels next to a cocker spaniel. A Christmas wreath hangs on the front door. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 32)
  - Warren Plath (photographer). Aurelia PlathApril 21, 1946, Black and white photograph. 6.5 x 9 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: Spring 1946. "Mummy" in her Easter finery! Warren took this snap of me. Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Aurelia Plath Stamp on verso: 880Z VELOX Subject: Three quarter view of Aurelia Plath (1906-1994) standing outside the front door at her home in Wellesley, Massachusetts. © Warren Plath (Helle 33)
  - Anonymous. Sylvia Plath sunbathing in the backyard at WellesleyJune 1946, Black and white photograph. 9 x 6.5 cm.; Caption on recto by Aurelia Schober Plath: 1946 (14) Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: June 1946. Sylvia has gained a few pounds since June & it shows becomingly. Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Age 14 Stamped on verso: 007Z VELOX Subject: Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) sunbathing on a blanket in her backyard in Wellesley, Massachusetts. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 34)
  - Anonymous. Sylvia Plath holding G.I. (dog)[October 1946], Black and white photograph. 6.5 x 9 cm.; Printed caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: The dog belongs to my brother, who calls him "G.I." Sylvia, age 14, and G.I.-age 2 months. Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Sylvia Plath and "friend." Stamped on verso: 309 Subject: Three quarter view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) holding her uncle's cocker spaniel near the back fence in Wellesley, Massachusetts. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 35)
  - Anonymous. Sylvia and Warren Plath holding G.I (dog)[October 1946], Black and white photograph. 6.5 x 9 cm.; Caption on verso: This doesn't do Sylvia justice but is excellent of Warren (age 11½) Stamped on verso: 309 VELOX Subject: Three quarter view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) and Warren Plath (1935- ) holding his uncle's cocker spaniel, in the side yard at Wellesley, Massachusetts. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 36)
  - Anonymous. Warren and Sylvia PlathMay 1947, Black and white photograph. 6.5 x 9 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: May 1947 Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Warren and Sylvia Plath (Ages 13 & 15). Stamp on verso: 618 Subject: Warren Plath (1935- ) wearing a suit and tie standing near a birch tree in the yard at Wellesley, Massachusetts. Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) is seated with a flower in her hair. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 37)
  - Anonymous. Sylvia Plath in the garden May 1947, Black and white photograph. 6.5 x 9 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: May 1947 Sylvia, 14½ years old Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Sylvia Plath Stamped on verso: 618 VELOX Subject: Three quarter view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) kneeling next to a bush in the garden at Wellesley, Massachusetts. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 38)
  - Anonymous. Aurelia Schober PlathMay 1947, Black and white photograph. 6.5 x 9 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: 1947 Caption on verso by June Johnson Helle: Aurelia Plath Stamped on verso: 618 VELOX Subject: Full view of Aurelia Schober Plath (1906-1994) seated in the yard at her home in Wellesley, Massachusetts. She is wearing a floral hat. © Unlnown (Helle 39)
  - Anonymous. Sylvia Plath sunbathingAugust 1947, Black and white photograph. 6.5 x 9 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: Sylvia, August 1947 14 years, 10 months Stamped on verso: 243 Subject: Full view of Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) seated in the lawn at her home in Wellesley, Massachusetts. She is drinking from a glass and has a pad of drawing paper nearby. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 40)
  - Anonymous. Warren and Sylvia PlathSeptember 1948, Black and white photograph. 9 x 6.5 cm.; Caption on verso by Aurelia Schober Plath: Warren & Sylvia, Sept. 1948 Stamped on verso: 994W VELOX Subject: Head and shoulders view of Warren Plath (1935- ) and Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) sitting near the front walk of their home in Wellesley, Massachusetts, with petunias in the background. © Estate of Aurelia Schober Plath (Helle 41)